foreign
[Music]
hello welcome to the round table this is
Round Table number 21 and I'm your host
Gonzalo Lira and today is uh Tuesday
September 20th 2022 and we're going to
have a very interesting discussion I
have three wonderful guests and I'll
introduce them to you in turn Ray
McGovern is a former CIA officer Ray
how's it going good to see you my friend
doing well thank you oh it's a pleasure
having you on again uh I have John
kiriaku the famous CIA whistleblower
John a pleasure to meet you the
pleasure's online Gonzalo thanks so much
for the invitation oh thank you very
much for accepting it's it's a real
pleasure a real delight and Susie Dawson
uh a activist on the intelligence front
Susie nice to meet you nice to meet you
sir Gonzalez thank you so much for
coming on and uh the thing that the the
reason I wanted to have you on is the
listeners know that uh I was away for
almost two weeks because my YouTube
channel got uh suspended got a strike
because I talked about the malady that
shall not be named so you all three are
warmed we cannot mention the malady or
much less the medication that's been
used for it but talking about that
forthrightly is no longer possible and
what I found fascinating is all these
Revelations whereby the US government is
working with these private platforms to
essentially censor information now I
actually lived in the Peniche
dictatorship I always bring this up that
in the paretedic chairship there was
less repression and more free speech in
the west than there in Chile back in the
day than there is in the west today and
I'm I wonder the the thing that I I find
fascinating is how the government has
outsourced repressive technology
measures and I want to get your uh
opinion John because you're you're like
you were one of the first whistleblowers
that started talking about the excesses
of the uh American intelligence
community and I want to get your opinion
about what you think of how the US
government is outsourcing repression uh
what do you think of all this oh yeah
well you know it's a it's a very
appropriate uh question because today is
the 75th anniversary of the creation of
the CIA uh I didn't know that yeah yeah
that's kind of funny yeah
we I've been thinking about this a lot
lately because uh there have been calls
uh from some important people people who
might have a great deal of respect for
uh who create a new church committee or
something akin to a new church committee
uh you know the church committee did
wonderful historic amazing work and
exposing crimes that the CIA and the FBI
were committing against Americans and
against uh uh foreign Nationals well
post 911 and and don't forget that 21
years have already passed since 9 11. uh
the the reforms that the church
committee enacted
have really just Fallen by the wayside
uh we've got a CIA now that has an
active assassination program a CIA that
won't even acknowledge that there is
such a thing as a drone program a CIA
that had a a secret prison system around
the world a CIA that carries out
International kidnappings that they
euphemistically call Renditions
there are there are so many things that
the CIA is doing in in the name of the
American people
for which there is no oversight or very
little oversight that it's essentially
undone all of the good things that the
church committee had accomplished the
FBI is is just as bad NSA is just as bad
you know it's a part of the nsa's
charter
that it's not permitted to collect
information on American citizens or U.S
persons that's any anybody here on a on
a green card
um and in fact that's almost exclusively
what they do uh we haven't even begun
talking about DARPA and about uh the the
Myriad of of contractors and uh
defense and intelligence related uh
consulting firms around the Beltway here
in Washington you know Gonzalo it's not
an accident that there are now more
millionaires per capita in the
Washington DC area than anywhere else in
America including Silicon Valley
it's not an accident yeah I know it got
very rich
911 and its aftermath but what I find
what I find incredible is is how so many
of the repressive measures that are
being implemented by the American
government are being subcontracted out
ability
absolutely I mean look at look at what
they call them butts in the seats that
that's the that's what they call them at
the CIA there are people who don't
really work for the CIA they work for
Booz Allen Hamilton or they work for
saic or happy or any any one of a number
of uh of outfits uh and they have a bud
in a seat and they they punch in
information in a computer or they you
know run some clandestine program
um the CIA doesn't have to pay for their
health insurance or their pension
contribution and uh and then everybody's
happy but then at the same time even
while everybody's happy there's no
accountability there's nobody that that
has to answer to anyone again you know
one of the great things that came out of
the church committee was the creation of
the Senate select committee on
intelligence and the house permanent
select committee on intelligence as the
oversight committees for the
intelligence Community well they're
they're just cheerleading organizations
yeah that oversee anything
yeah you know I saw a video of yours
Susie that that how you discussed the um
the the the the motivation of these
intelligence firms since there are for
profit corporations they want to be
increasing their revenue and so
basically they start targeting everybody
yeah well that's the problem when you
subcontract
um the targeting of citizens to
for-profit agencies in order for them to
make more profit they need to Target
more people and I think I I mentioned
and I think I know the film that you're
talking about and I mentioned in there
how when security cameras first came
into residential areas or commercial
districts you know you had like one
camera and then another kilometer One
camera and then it was like 800 meters
and it was 600 meters and now you have
four cameras on the same wall of the
same shop and um it's just this cycle
where to make more money they're
actually Target more people
um
did you hear about how there's an AI
that if you take a picture on Instagram
this AI can look at the picture and
figure out which cameras were filming
you while you took the picture and and
and show them to you and this is a
commercially available product that is
for people people's Amusement so in
terms of intelligence you can imagine
how much you're being surveilled yeah
absolutely and studying NSA documents
from Snowden Falls you see the same
thing they talk about wanting to be able
to geolocate to the meter anywhere on
the planet no matter which country it's
in they do it from space and National
geospatial agency later in our uh as
well in this sorry National surveillance
officers I think Ray would know
um there's a whole bunch of these
agencies that are aside from the CIA and
NSA which are part of this ecosystem of
spying and their agencies that in some
cases have more Personnel than NSA or
CIA but which nobody ever even hears
about but they're end game and they
admit it in their own documents that the
end game is to create a control grid of
the entire planet it's it's in black and
white in their own documents it's
basically a panopticon a panopticon
prison where where the warden can see
every single prisoner and and nobody can
make a move without any any kind of
Freedom Ray let me ask you to bring you
into the conversation you know how do we
solve this what would be the Practical
steps necessary in order to change this
around and have an intelligence service
that does its job but serves the people
and doesn't try to in essence it seems
to me kind of like enslave the people
well Gonzalo I I uh compliment you on
your Greek derivative
panopticon yeah it literally means see
everything you know
uh and that's pretty much as Susie has
already indicated the name of the game
now I'd like to go back to what uh John
kiriapo said uh he's an expert on
torture having refused to be trained in
the techniques of enhanced interrogation
techniques
and having blown the whistle on it now
it's very courageous thing to do uh it
ended it ended up with him having to
spend two years in prison
I visited John in prison I saw all kinds
of folks were there with John and Howard
was so glad that John could defend
himself
uh that's neither here nor there let's
talk about the so-called
oversight committees right well long
since they have become
Overlook committees you know the
overlooked Committees of the Senate and
the house
now just yesterday
a federal judge or district judge a
ruled that we are not allowed to see the
extensive
6700 page
Senate intelligence committee research
document on CIA
torture based on CIA
documents okay
now
people need to be reminded how this
evolved
it took five years to do it started out
when
when under the order of Gina haspel the
chief CIA person in the first CIA black
site in Thailand waterboarding and worse
we're done okay she was there she
watched it she wasn't right there she
washed it through the proverbial window
make sure as you know what she wanted
okay now the tapes that were made were
destroyed by whom oh fight you an
and her boss now even a
Republican senator was outraged at then
we have to
later the Republicans bowed out of the
investigation but what came out of that
was a really gutsy report shepherded by
Dianne Feinstein who unfortunately is
now in her dotage but in those days
uncharacteristically I think because she
stood up for these people that she saw
working night and day to get to the
bottom of this and who came by quite
quite felicitously
serious
bear
original studies done at the behest of
the then CIA director Leon Panetta I
mean they had all the goods right there
okay now what happened
they started drafting this thing and
President Obama was opposed to it he had
his chief of staff attend all of these
meetings that were sensibly designed to
to redact it to to sanitize it okay
every one of those meetings what did
this person do I think it was McCullough
is that his name anyhow uh he was there
to make sure that the CI interests were
protected why because John Brennan and
Barack Obama uh had this twin
relationship where Barack Obama was
going to do everything he possibly could
to defend John Brennan
now when it came out that John Brennan
sent his folks into the Senate
intelligence committee computers
Dianne Feinstein got a little girl got a
little upset at that okay suffice it to
say that she oversaw a document of 6700
pages but
reduced to 525 page redacted executive
summary now the summary is enough to
indict everyone involved the summary is
awful you you have to the the summary
yeah just the summary I mean it's Street
active but you learn that
these these terrible techniques and
they're named were not effective they
didn't produce any valid information
that the CIA lied about it to the
president and to everyone else that oh
yeah we're getting good information on
tourism and anything and that the
techniques themselves were followers
than any briefed to the White House or
to anybody else okay those were the main
conclusions and gory detail is included
now what happened
it's the end of Dianne Feinstein's term
as head of the Senate select committee
on intelligence what's she gonna do is
she going to go ahead and publish this
redacted summary or is she going to Bow
like most people and do Overlook crowded
and oversight
I don't know what accounted for her
courage I think it was her loyalty to
these folks who worked so hard for her
okay who did so much and came up with
this redacted versions which spoke
volumes in and of themselves but she was
also helped by a senator named Udall
you don't lost this re-election
capability and you'd all said you know
if you don't release that terrible
document I'm gonna release it from the
floor of Congress
whoa that that allowed or propelled even
Obama to say okay we redacted the 525
page summary so all right let it go out
there and we just will tell the Press
don't play it up it's just you know
we're trying to catch terrorists right
okay yeah so that so it's published in
December of
2014 I think okay so what happens
um it's pretty much kept the wraps on uh
and when Richard Burr I live in North
Carolina now uh he's still one of our
Senators when he became chair of the
Senate intelligence committee replacing
Dianne Feinstein he said those are
congressional documents I want them all
back here I'm going to take care of them
every one of you executive agencies give
me those documents
and they did now I I suspect that there
may have been one kept at the CIA but I
also suspect that cheetah haspel
destroyed that before she left office as
get this director of the CIA what's the
morale what's the moral of this story
well uh not only are the Senate and
House intelligence committees
feckless
and unable to do what the what the
commission asked them to do very early
on uh but they're actually facilitate
the hiding of these things and I dare
say they know that the CI the FBI have
as much on them as as would be very
embarrassing or they just step out of
line and do the right thing lastly
Richard Burr was caught
selling stock when code when he got a
briefing on Covert and he he just you
know really just did what he could to
enhance his profits that's well known
he's going out of out of office in
January and the sooner the better but
you know it's not only he I'll just add
one more thing
the Senate
Judiciary Committee
headed by a super annuated guy from Iowa
whose name will occur to me in a second
John cariako you probably will Grassley
okay all right so here what happens with
respect to Watergate is this lawyer
kleinsmith is discovered to have
falsified documents to justify a fisa
request okay okay what does he get well
his wife is pregnant and so he gets no
jail time okay for deliberately
falsifying this document okay that's a
felony okay so what happens grassly
comments
in a in a we call it
of a tweet okay a grassly queen and he
says oh so this this shows that the
justice department has no power over
these over these people uh what happens
is uh it's the department of just us is
what Wesley says and no one will ever go
to no one ever go to jail they take care
of themselves now why is the significant
regressively is the chairman of the them
or almost chairman now he has been
Germany he'll be chairman again probably
of the Senate uh Judiciary Committee
he's 91 years old I think that's even
older than I am I think he's even less
accomplishmentous than I am sorry to
carry on so long that's all right that's
all right it's it's delightful to hear
you uh but you know one of the things I
notice and uh John help me out here
because it seems to me that the uh Obama
administration oddly enough the Democrat
Administration that's all for civil
liberties and you know free speech and
all the rest of it it seemed to be more
obsessed with intelligence and cracking
down on intelligence
I had friends at the White House at the
time who described Barack Obama's
obsession with leaks as nixonian it was
a nicksonian obsession with National
Security leaks and I was told also at
the time that this was because of John
Brennan remember Obama tried to name
Brennan as CIA director uh in
2009 at the beginning of his first term
and progressives just threw a fit and so
so Obama the thing is I just want to be
clear I'm I'm politically conservative
and very conservative that and I think
that John Brennan is just you know he is
he looks like a shyster you know drug
dealer almost I mean I would trust him
as far as I could throw him to tell you
the truth so I understand the
progressives exactly you know there's
there's actually a great story to the
career of John Brennan I I worked for
John Brennan when I was still on the
analytics side at the CIA uh John was a
gs-15 uh Deputy Chief of the Arab
Israeli group in the office of near
Eastern South Asian analysis okay he was
a mid-level functionary like so many of
us were
and um he worked for a woman named
Martha Kessler who was like the U.S
government's leading expert on Syria
Martha wrote a book called Syria fragile
Mosaic of power that we all had to read
when we went oh god oh oh so she could
get you know pick up some royalties
right
he worked for her but she didn't like
him and finally he went to her this was
in this was in like
1996 I'm gonna say and
um 1995. and uh he said look I've worked
for you for a long time I think I'm
ready for promotion into the senior
intelligence service and she said
that not only will you never be in the
senior intelligence service I don't even
want you working for me anymore you're
fired
and at the agency when you're fired
fired you're not really fired you have
six weeks to to walk the halls and find
another job and if you do you're good
and if you don't then you're fired right
six weeks within within the agency
itself within the agency exactly well
it's Christmas time and you know the
normal turnover for jobs is in the
summer so John goes out there and he
starts looking for a job he ends up
going to the pdb staff the president's
Daily Brief where where Ray was uh was a
star
and because it was off cycle
uh they were able to offer him a job as
a briefer for the lowest ranking person
entitled to a pdb briefing that was the
director of intelligence programs at the
National Security Council who at the
time happened to be one George tenant
so yeah they immediately hit it off
because they were exactly alike their
mean aggressive alpha dogs cigar smoking
you know just two awful people hit it up
George was promoted to Deputy uh
director of the CIA and he brings uh
John Brennan back with him and what does
he do he makes John Brennan deputy
director of The Office of near Eastern
and South Asian analysis Martha
Kessler's boss
so John calls Martha oh his office oh
now you're fired
okay I mean I gotta admit as a story
it's pretty good and and pretty sweet
for Brennan I mean let's give the devil
his Jew the thing the devil is exactly
how he should be described oh yeah this
is exactly how he should be describing
Susie can you give us background on John
Brennan because
you don't want to I I absolutely no I
think it's important to actually because
there's a trail of dead bodies behind
John Brennan not many people talk about
and I don't actually just mean
um those that you would assume in the
war on terror
um but I mean actually on Western soil
and particularly journalists and Brennan
was the attack dog of Obama that is true
but Brennan absolutely relished the role
and Brennan had very personal beefs with
Julian Assange and with Wikileaks but
also with someone else who almost never
gets talked about in fact has almost
been disappeared from the discourse
that's an extremely Brave Rolling Stone
reporter called Michael Hastings Michael
Hastings was going on CNN and MSNBC and
major mainstream platforms and he was
completely eviscerating the Obama
Administration the war on terror
particularly the military U.S military
effort in Afghanistan he wrote an
extremely famous expose on it was
General Stanley mcquisto am I right Ray
yes right who ended up getting fired by
Obama on the basis of the reporting of
Michael Hastings well Michael Hastings
was also the first famous or earliest
famous reporter outside of Glenn and
Glenn Greenwood and Laura poitrus to
openly support Snowden and when I say
support Snowden I mean in the minutes
after Snowden coming out when before he
had even left Hong Kong when everybody
was waking up every day expecting that
they would see the news that Snowden had
been captured or killed Michael Hastings
go and look at his Twitter timeline at
MM Hastings and see the tweets I'm
talking about more than 50 percent of
his tweets on his timeline were
advocating for Snowden far and wide and
that was at a time where it was
extremely dangerous to support Snowden
in those first minutes and hours and
days after the first known disclosures
Michael Hastings was also working on his
next big story at that time and his next
big story was an expose on Ron Brennan
then director of the CIA
likely in the context of Brennan's
targeting of Julian Assange and
Wikileaks who Hastings had also been
outspoken and supportive Hastings had
met with Julian several times Hastings
had written a series of articles about
Julian and Wikileaks
um so Hastings was on the proverbial
list I don't know what else to call
it for a number of reasons but having
taken down a general having supported
Wikileaks and Julian throughout the
smear campaigns and the the D
platforming and the attacks that
Wikileaks was facing in that period of
2009 through 2013 then openly advocating
for Snowden and then the final straw
endearing to investigate the director of
the CIA John Brennan and it will expose
him for his own criminality uh Michael
Hastings then reported that he believed
his cut his vehicle was being tampered
with he borrowed a neighbor's car he
reached out to Jen Robinson Wikileaks
lawyer and shared his fears that he was
being targeted by the FBI and has
his car his late model BMW borrowed from
the neighbor in fact
um exploded into some of the reins on a
Los Angeles Boulevard
um less than 48 hours after he first
started complaining to those around him
that he was in fear and he was being
severely targeted by U.S intelligence
agencies that is a U.S citizen on U.S
soil
um exercising their first amendment
rights exercising their political
freedoms doing so to enormous audiences
and with the motivation of protection of
Truth tell us and um you know be it
Julian be at Snowden bit whoever and
um we needed that voice and we needed
that voice
no we need that voice now we've needed
it ever since 2013. that voice was
silence and the there was to be an
investigation it was swiftly covered up
everything was smoothed over and now
nobody speaks the name Michael Hastings
so
um in respects to Michael and the work
that he did I wanted to tell that story
now and also there was something else
that made me think of it and that's
John's sacrifice because John right here
is why the world knows about CAA torture
John is why Obama had to address it John
is why there was a report and that we
have the information that we do have and
John has paid a deep price for that as
well so I just want to show respect to
you too John you're amazing
yeah
go ahead go ahead you don't have to ask
permission no
well you know I'm a Catholic and I
always ask for permission
um
I'm a lapsed Catholic I have found it
it's easier to ask for forgiveness than
permission
[Laughter]
with respect to Hastings thanks so much
Susie for bringing that into a wider
view
um what happened to uh Hastings I can be
readily explained by something that
Julian Assange himself
revealed and that is a so-called set of
offensive cyber War tactics
that came out of this Bevy of things
that were released what was they a
minute uh Vault 17. yeah both seven yeah
okay now just to remind folks uh there
were all kinds of really fancy
techniques that the CIA had had
devised and implemented one of them was
you could be asleep in your bedroom and
uh you'd think that your TV was off
right I think I think again the TV is
recording everything going on in your
bedroom right well another one of these
offensive cyber tools was the ability to
take control of a late model car using
its computer system Make It Go 100 miles
an hour without any intervention by
breaks or anything else and cause a
crash yeah now
um
it's actually quite easy you know it
could also be done on motorcycles I know
more about on motorcycles but yeah
John kirocco knows about motorcycles so
yeah you could tell that one anyhow what
I want to say is uh the rest of the
Susie's story is ironically explained I
think by volt seven uh documents and um
and that this is uh partly why uh the
new CIA director of Pompeo uh branded uh
Julian a
non-state terrorist outfit or is that
what they call them
yeah non-state hostile intelligence
agency and that's when they really
started going after him using the
Ecuadorian uh patsies to to get him out
Adam finally you know there's background
to that too uh which I didn't realize
until after the fact but if if the CIA
director declares an organization a
non-state
um actor then the law says that the
agency is exempt from Port from
informing the oversight committees if
there's an operation against it well you
know it's it's all like legalistic
I mean you're you're making up
your rules so that you can follow these
new rules to get what you want so you
know it's it's legalistic I I
can't think of a nicer term for this and
by the way you can curse all you want
this channel is demonetized I'm not
making a penny off of these videos so
you know cursor yeah you know although
Rey being a good Catholic boy he might
get get the vapors actually actually I
should revise that I made John 23 uh
Progressive Catholic and the pope and I
have very little in common except for
one thing
that is when in 2015
he had the guts to stand up before a
joint
Congress and say you know the main
problem is the blood-drenched arms trade
and all those congressmen got up and
said yes
see the latest envelope from Lockheed
and yeah
giving hypocrisy a bad name okay but he
had it had his thumb on it
why he doesn't act on it is still
complicated but we don't wait for the
book Tech these days we do it ourselves
but John to get back to your point of
calling Julian Assange a a non-state
intelligence service you know I mean
like
how how is it possible that people just
accept this because my thinking on the
Julian Assange and I really want to have
Susie on but I I guess if something's
happened to her and she'll be back all
right there she is well I want to bring
the conversation to Julian Assange
because from my point of view number one
he has not committed any crime in the
United States number two he's not a U.S
citizen number three whenever the the
government documents were released he
was not in the United States at the time
so how on Earth can you justify
Prosecuting a man who didn't commit a
crime in the United States is not a U.S
citizen and the crime itself is not
committed on American soil I mean yeah
you're you're exactly right and I think
that's frankly the argument that his
attorneys are going to make too besides
the flat the fact that this is a very
very slippery slope
hang on John let me rephrase my question
why is it that the intelligence Services
hate this guy so much why him
specifically because I've never quite
understood there have been other leakers
all right I'm I'm saying this with with
uh respect of course you yourself were a
whistleblower and I'm sure a lot of
people at CIA were unhappy with you for
you know informing on the things that
you did but why is it that this guy
Julian Assange is hated so desperately
inside and such a psychopathic way what
was it that triggered this boundless
hatred for the man and we all have
different answers for that I've
definitely got one but take before okay
let's go piece by piece we'll go we'll
go John John Susie and Ray you know just
to keep some semblings Because by the
way I'm gonna I'm gonna mute my camera
but I'm just going out to I'm just
smoking a cigarette I'm still here okay
go ahead please John so why do they hate
it I'm told that it's it's twofold the
reason is twofold uh first it's because
he was doing it with impunity he was
urging people to uh send documents he
was offering protection and and you know
he was taking talking uh people's
personal security very seriously they
were redacting documents to protect uh
the identities of people that just
enraged them the other thing and and I'm
told this is what sort of pushed the
agency over the edge was the release of
the Vault 7 documents uh those were the
most uh sensitive most important crown
jewels perhaps ever in the history of
the CIA that was just that was just too
much for them bridge too far so they've
gone after him like they have
but I mean it's been years now I mean he
was in that uh Ecuadorian prison for
what seven years I mean all together
this drama has been going on for 10. and
I mean how does anybody endure that that
that just uh um that hatred for so long
now Susie you have a different View
well there's different sides to Julian
there's Julian the technologists and
software apart who devised the first
ever encrypted Dropbox for
whistleblowers what later
um secure drop was modeled off of even
though some claim otherwise it was it
has proven to be
um there was Julian the Deep political
thinker who was a walking encyclopedia
who had studied so many tens of
thousands hundreds of thousands millions
of documents that he possessed a
uniquely
uh diverse and just profound
understanding of how the agencies worked
how the world worked how zero politics
work and was sharing that with other
people there was Julian my mentor and
the mentor of many independent
Independent Media people he would take
people under his wing he would lift them
up he would platform them he would give
them a name give them exposure spread
their work share their work
um there was just on in that regard he
was always increasing the number of us
that were working on this type of thing
um but probably most importantly of all
and I think personally what they hate
him for the most is there's Julian who
is the only man on the planet who had
the ability to add a whim sees the
global media narrative when Julian was
free and working even when he was in the
Ecuadorian Embassy not really free but
still able to work
the Empire of Lies would have to chase
Julian's narrative Chase Wikileaks
narrative Chase Wikileaks work they were
never able to drive that narrative and
you see since they have seized Julian
kidnapped him from the embassy since
they have silenced him they have finally
for the first time and the better part
of a decade regained control of that
narrative and now they are driving the
narrative now all everything you see in
the media everything we're discussing
you know it's the Russia gate it's the
covert it's the whatever is next it's
Ukraine it's whatever this is all being
planned strategically planned and
devised and implemented by the people
who were on the back foot through all
those years of Julian's
um I nearly said Julian's Reign it was
Julian's reign in terms of control of
narrative and I cannot think of any
other person on this planet who is able
to direct the focus and attention of the
media class of the political class and
of the intelligence agencies the way
that he did and that made him uniquely
terrifying to them completely terrifying
and they also need they need to make an
example of him because their deepest
fear is the other Julians rise and
achieve the same thing and I'd like to
as my final thought on this point out
that Julian was the crash test I mean
for D platforming Julian was unpersoned
as you say before anybody else was
Julian was cut off from PayPal Julian's
bank cards were shut down Julian went
through the massive smear trolling
campaigns online defamation campaigns
Julian was subjected to the false
charges false allegations Julian was
hung out to dry first and that template
now we see being used against with
greater and greater frequency against
more and more people yeah and that has
now become part of the for-profit model
there is now for-profit agencies that
not just Target for silencing but smear
anti-platform and every everybody is
being made into a Julian Assange because
they were able to get away with what
they did to him and now they think they
have free license so that is why they
hate Julian to the end of time
yeah Ray what are your thoughts
well I agree with everything that's been
said by Susie and by John and I have
other things that they hate him for
you know I'm reminded of a
of my youth when we used to have Gene
Autry uh pictures okay and he used to be
driving he'd be riding through this uh
this terrible Rock fill landscape and oh
the iragosa Indians are over there they
hate you not tree and they say why do
you hate they hate Gene Autry from
another picture
okay so the reason the powers that be
hate Julian Assange is from lots of
other pictures and I'll just fill in
some of the blanks that I think may
arise first off uh Julie Susie put her
her finger on it uh back when Julian
first appeared the fourth estate was
well on life support
the fluster state was as The Princess
Bride would say almost mostly then
mostly dead it was mostly okay and Here
Comes The Fifth Estate with an
instantaneous way of getting valid stuff
out into the ether and down into
computers whoa it was a difference in
kind okay it was a shock and what did
these things include not only war crimes
in Afghanistan or Iraq but things like
warnings
one specific one I'll sight warnings by
Sergey lavrov
the Russian foreign minister
on the first of February 2008
calling in Bill Burns
who ironically is now the CIA who was
Ambassador in Moscow okay call him in
his Mr Burns do you know what nietz
means
if you allow Ukraine into NATO we are
going to have to retaliate because this
is this is a bridge too far we will have
to decide whether we have to inter
intervene invade Ukraine so please tell
your people tell your people this
Condoleezza Rice at the time for God's
sake tell your people now Burns to his
credit played it straight which have the
cable if I've seen one cable from Moscow
Embassy I've seen about 8 000 of them
okay we have the cable Wikileaks made it
available that the title of Burns's
cable is niet means yet Russia's red
lines on Ukraine advancement into NATO
it went through the whole nine yards
suffice it to say that's really really
bad for the people who want to who want
to fool around with Ukraine want to fool
around with the west of the rest of
Eastern Europe now the couple other
things I'll be briefer here
um
2016. the unpardonable sin not mentioned
yet
but he published documents
from the Democratic National Committee
that showed that
show that Hillary had stolen the
nomination from Bernie Sanders pure and
simple yeah they were right there yeah
right there in black and white there's
another unpardonable sin okay that's
2016. now the other thing is Snowden
Ed Snowden what a patriot you know
what a patriot what'd he did okay now
Snowden got out of Hong Kong
Snowden happens to be a friend of mine
I've met him a couple of times he lives
pretty good life now he's got a little
boy they live
in Russia let's just say that okay now
how was it
how was it that what everyone from the
CIA to to the most to the least liaison
service was looking for for it's a how
do you get out I don't ever float
playing of all things it was surely an
Assange he called in all his chips from
that part of the world Susie probably
knows his brother and I do but well I'll
what I'll but I'll include here is a
little vignette last time I saw Julian
or maybe it was next to the last it was
in the embassy in Ecuador I said Julian
you know I admire a lot of things that
you've done all right
but none more than getting it snowed in
out of out of Hong Kong so he could be
free
and Julian is not a he's sort of a tax
return person normally but he jumped off
the couch and he said yes
yes that I fellow Lake Ed Snowden would
not be not suffer the fate of so many
others so there again uh this was
against the the uh the Deep State and
finally as has been mentioned Vault
seven man that was just that was those
of the Family Jewels and everybody knows
about them now and that of course was
somebody who had some patriotic
instincts within the NSA
apparently according to what's been in
the price and gave them to Julian and
Julian was
circumspecting at first in publicizing
the ones but when negotiations for his
release fell apart and this is on very
good authority when people intervened
like the head of the Senate intelligence
committee intervene and said no no we're
not going to bargain with Julian Assange
he said all right the whole nine yards
gets released now and that's when you
got all virtually all of of all seven so
here there's a Litany of sins for which
uh for which Julian would be put in at
least Purgatory probably hell forever
together with Don Rumsfeld and all those
other guys uh if the Deep state had had
its way
I I I want to focus on both of those
issues that you raise array and so I'll
start with you Susie is how exactly did
Julian help Edward Snowden get to Moscow
uh because that seems to be a a spy
story and and I don't know if you guys
know that uh after college I got my
start writing in Hollywood and I wrote a
couple of Thrillers and I haven't
written a thriller since then but you
know this might make for a good thriller
so Susie could you fill us in on those
details
it's the best thriller really
um it was in hot water
it applied for Refugee status in Hong
Kong at
um Wikileaks suggestion edit had reached
out to WikiLeaks
um and it wanted to keep distance
actually it made a lot of very Noble
decisions that were uh probably to his
detriment at the time
um but he wanted to keep distance
between himself and the the reporters he
didn't want to contribute in any way to
detracting from the potency of the
stories that were being reported based
on the documents which he had leaked so
he leaked when I say electric she didn't
really use that term because it's not
really true he leaked to the journalists
for them to use their journalistic
skills and expertise to filter through
and to report on the content
um so he found himself somewhat adrift
in Hong Kong for a period of time and so
this has been covered extensively
elsewhere so I won't go too much into
detail he was taken care of by some
other asylums again is in Hong Kong for
a short period of time while there was a
literal Manhunt on for him yeah and
probably the extent and veracity of that
meant Hunter's not been reported on so
much to date but suffice it to say I
would say that half of the spies in
South Asia had been rerouted to Hong
Kong to go for him uh in that period of
time
and fortunately Julian decided to take a
few extra steps and first thing Heely
did was send an extremely Brave
journalist Sarah Harrison who was then a
Publications editor for Wikileaks to
Hong Kong to meet up with Snowden from
that point they got a really great legal
counsel International wise as well and
they managed to get
Snowden out of Hong Kong originally he
was to go to Ecuador via Cuba I believe
but that fell through by this point it
wasn't just a spies on The Manhunt it
was International media leader as well
he had a slew of MSM reporters flying
various places around the world and
booking themselves on flights definitely
because desperately thinking that they
were going to be able to sit next to
Snowden and ask all the questions of
course Julian however had booked Snowden
onto Myriad flights on Myriad Airlines
to Myriad locations in order to obscure
snowden's actual path of Escape
he flew from Hong Kong it was quite
famously known I think that the US had
Frozen snowden's passport however they
had managed to misspell his middle name
in the order to cancel his passport and
so the Hong Kong authorities have said
we're sorry but this documentation is
actually not accurate therefore we can't
apply this order and um
it was a really brilliant press
statement actually put out by the Hong
Kong authorities at the time which
explained exactly how how this
administrative mistake had occurred
which had allowed Snowden to escape and
then and the next paragraph It said In
the meantime you know Snowden documents
expose you were spying on Chinese
University students blah blah blah so it
was absolutely hilarious obviously
somebody made a decision that um they
should buy the book to the documentation
which was inaccurate and therefore
allows Simone to leave uh Snowden was
transiting through Russia and um at that
point his passport was canceled red
notice was issued etc etc and he ended
up stuck in the transit lounge with
Sarah Harrison for some it was
definitely more than 30 days I can't
remember I want to say 36 or something
like that days here in the meantime he
applied for temporary Asylum and a large
number of countries all of which got the
U.S state Department called threatening
them with God knows what if they
accepted the temporary Asylum claim and
ultimately Russia granted him to
temporary Asylum because what else can
they do they can't let them live in the
airport for the rest of his life so
um and in the meantime of course Very
helpfully you had heads of U.S
intelligence agencies threatening to
kill him or jail him for his life on
International television which is pretty
good evidence for an asylum claim so
that's how that happened but it was
absolutely Julian Wikileaks Wikileaks
funds and network that were used to save
Stone's life and Julian did say on
multiple occasions that this was a
watershed moment it was important to
show
that if people were to take the brave
step of leaking of sharing the truth
with the public that there were others
and other avenues that would help and
assist them and that there would be an
opportunity for them to achieve some
level of safety uh and to and even to be
able to work in Snowden has done all
types of amazing and incredible work
since his life was so by Julian
while we're waiting for it go ahead Ray
go ahead Ray please you know thanks
Susie that's really really helpful that
background is essential I would add just
two small things
um now when this unprecedented worldwide
investigation to try to find uh Ed
Snowden was in train they were looking
at all the likely places right I mean
they were looking in all the high rises
and all the fancy hotels in in Hong Kong
and they were looking among the Upper
Crust okay
thank you
Julian was nowhere to be found I mean Ed
was nowhere to be found he you know my
Irish grandmother told me about the
Upper Crust she said there's a bunch of
crumbs held together by a lot of dough
okay now now those crumbs
I'm gonna steal it by the way yeah
please yeah the Upper Crust a bunch of
crumbs held together by a lot of dough
okay well he was not among the Upper
Crust he was somewhere else this is no
secret now it's been sort of revealed
Julian had this incredible capability to
tap into what's needed you know and he
was a friend of oppressed people too
people living on the margins and people
not living in the high rises in Hong
Kong okay so that's that's another
little facet of the story I hope you'll
agree with that Susie okay the other
thing uh what's the other thing I was
gonna say oh yeah pooching foreign
well no he was asked you know he was
asked on film uh Mr President puccine do
you think that Ed Snowden did the right
thing
and Putin says no
it didn't do the right thing
well then why did you give him uh why
did you give him
permanent sound now no well permanent
residency technically okay and now
citizenship got it but poaching said
well you know he didn't say what Susie
just said we're gonna leave him and shut
them yet to the airport forever he said
well uh nobody else would take them
and it's the right thing for for a
country to do to give political Asylum
and such cases so
now why did Putin say that no he didn't
agree with what what Ed Snowden did well
for God's sake is is the next kcb
officer is he going to say oh yeah
no no of course not
but when push came to shove he said I
followed at the national law here he
asked for Asylum nobody else would give
him Asylum everybody else was too afraid
of the United States I gave him Asylum
enough said yeah that's the issue I
wanted to raise with both of you and and
with John when he comes when he hops
back on
um do you guys think that this affected
uh uh the West's uh reaction towards
it's not or not not not the west but
rather the intelligence service that
they just had it in for Putin over
Julian over uh Ed Snowden did this
affect their their view of Putin or do
you think it was you know minor just a
blip on the road
I'm going to lean on the amazing MI6
whistleblower Annie Marshawn who's the
only person that I've seen to date who
made the very astute observation that
the
vitriol the hatred with which with has
targeted Russia particularly since 2013
is a absolutely in direct relation to uh
them granting Asylum for Snowden
um that the whole Russia gate that
everything else that has been
you know
manufactured since then has been about
the defaming of Russia the
de-platforming of Russia that everything
else that we see is directly tied to
that that is the is it's not only for
that reason obviously there is
generations of beef underlying it but it
is absolutely a sticking point for them
and um such as I said in the case of
Julian they want to create a precedent
like they want to put the word out don't
even dare do this and of course they
have their own Workforce to worry about
and they were absolutely petrified post
noting that there would be other
snowdens from within the agencies and
they actually went to great they
introduced an entire like
um anti-snoden protocol where they
reworked all of their internal processes
and procedures to try and make sure that
they could identify the next note before
he ever even got out of the United
States let alone to pass documents here
and anyone else Etc so yeah I I
absolutely believe that's a factor in
this
and I respect greatly that um that all
of the people and countries and groups
that have one way or another
helped to get to preserve Snowden for
the world for all of us and I I wish
that we could achieve the same thing for
Julian I very much wish that yeah and
it's the thing is see uh and I mean no
disrespective to these two gentlemen
when when I say the following that see
uh uh Edward Snowden
um uh a brave man no question but the
fact is the information that he had
access to now that he is no longer an
American intelligence service or an
intelligence service subcontract
uh his danger into the future is fairly
limited whereas I think there's a
perception that if Julian Assange were
let loose he'd continue with Wikileaks
encouraging more people to come forward
with abuses and the illegalities and
your moralities and so I think that in
in a sense and and I don't mean this in
in any pejorative way but I think that
they're they're more afraid of Julian
Assange being free than Edward Snowden
being free do you see my rationale rate
would you agree
well I think it's hard to distinguish
these things
I would point out that again what what
Susie says is right on On Target any
Metro is one of the most dispute
political observers I've run into
but there's another factor in broader
geo-strategic terms 2013
um you know in some ways this was the
apogee now you'd be surprised to hear
this probably but this was the height of
friendly U.S Russian relations yeah how
so yeah this before before the coup of
uh 14 13 14 in in yeah well this is 13
we're talking about and coaching pulled
Obama's chestnuts out of the fire Obama
didn't want to start a war in Syria he
was under great pressure by all his
advisors and by Congress to do precisely
that poutine offered him a way out to
have those Syrian chemical weapons
destroyed under U.N supervision on a U.S
ship outfitted to destroy chemical
weapons that got Obama off the hook to
the point where the New York Times on
the 12th of September
2013 published an op-ed by Vladimir
which said you know our growing trust is
something I really relish not only the
trust between our countries but the
trust between our presidents President
Obama and myself the only thing I I
don't agree with President Obama on is
what he said last week that the U.S is
the sole exceptional country in the
world I don't think that makes sense I
there are there are poor Nations there
are nations close to the Democracy I I
think that God looks on all these
countries and finds no exceptional one
finds them all to be equal now
that threw down the gauntlet to people
like Victoria Noland and all these other
growing trust growing each other
six months later we have the coup in
Kiev on the maiden and you know the rest
of that story so you know it was uh you
know it was certainly Ed played into
this but also the geopolitical of things
here where you had the budding trust
here Obama grateful for it and Obama not
willing or able just to stand up to the
likes of
Victorian old and John Brennan and the
rest of the deep state which is a very
real entity
yeah I I mean this whole situation from
the world view of the Russians that they
helped them out in a serious situation
and all the rest is building trust and
then six months later they manufacture
the coup in in Kiev that was the wake-up
call for for the Russians that was when
they realized hey we're going to have a
war with these people so we have to
postpone this war so that we can prepare
and here we are you know in in the
middle of it
um I I wanted to bring I I wanted to
toss a question to John but John is
still not back with us but let me let me
intervene here it's not that the
Russians had to prepare
it's that NATO had to prepare a fighting
force
to force the Russians out of dunbas
we know what happened now John Brennan
John Brennan went to famous yeah right
after the coup and the idea was okay uh
we're gonna rebuild your forces we're
going to train ten thousand uh people uh
each each year and then we're going to
take back the dunbas and we're going to
threaten Russia okay now that's that's
what was in play here and pooching uh
was trying through what we'll call the
Minsk of chords which Ukraine had signed
up to and which Germany and France had
guaranteed uh which would have given
these provinces in the East uh vignetsk
and Logan's a measure of our autonomy
under the new Constitution that went by
the board and we have the former prime
minister of Ukraine owning up to the
fact that they were never taken Minsk
seriously it was just a stratagem to
postpone the years until they could get
trained up so that they could think on
the Russians and that happened what
2014 uh 2021 so you got six or seven
years uh and that's why Russia uh faced
a much more vulnerable folk than anyone
expected including perhaps the Russians
well no that's uh
I think that the Russians had a very
very clear idea at the biggest conflict
now in 2022 as to what they were dealing
with and they were very well prepared
for it and uh the the proof isn't the
pudding because people in the west have
noticed uh don't quite understand
um how this war has been prosecuted and
it's been this very slow grinding
process because it's been a deliberate
strategy of the Russian army to just
slowly be grinding away as opposed to
trying to make any dramatic and
spectacular move because they realize
that politically uh it's to their
advantage to make it a slow grinding
process that in essence bore is the West
because after seven months people are at
the end of their tether and of course
with the loss of energy resources Europe
in particular is is you know going
through Dire Straits and it's going to
get a lot worse in the winter and so the
the way the Russians have been handling
this war has been very effective uh but
I wanted to go back to
um the the famous Vault seven that you
and John um mentioned a couple of times
and I don't know what what's happened to
John I hope that you know he sorts out
his Communications issues because I
really wanted to bring him in what were
these crown jewels of Vault seven I mean
first of all what is Vault 7 and what is
what's in it and what was released
specifically that just made the CIA and
the intelligence Services of the United
States throw a hissy fit
so that intro at Ray and new Gap Phil
okay go go I'm sorry oh I said I'll
intro the Publications and and you can
Gap fill on whatever it is
oh my gosh
um okay so Vault seven was a Wikileaks
publication of a large case of documents
that had been supplied to them by a
whistleblower who some people think was
Joshua Schulte who is unfortunately an
extremely parallelistic consensus in a
U.S black site slash prison right now
and on on U.S soil he's an American
citizen the CIA whistleblower we don't
uh Julian would never confirms or denies
who the source of a Wikileaks
publication is so that's why I kind of
go around the issue there I can't
definitively say one way or the other
um as to who is the source but that's
who many people believe to be the source
can you repeat the name please Joshua
salty s c h u l t e am I correct Ray
correct
and he was CIA
he would have been a CIA contractor
um one of the bums on seats that John
karaoke was telling you about before
um he has been arrested he has um been
accused of uh possessing child
pornography which is this strange charge
that somehow seems to be applied to a
multitude of whistleblowers that end up
leaking files or documents uh Joshua
shelter is not the only leaker who we
has somehow then
um had the accusation labeled at him but
obviously they're far more concerned
about whether or not he actually leaks
these documents so
um Wikileaks always themed and named
their Publications so that they could
um promote and get the most uh possible
views for them which they did very
successfully so Vault 7 is the name that
they branded that publication they
released a series of uh very enigmatic
images that cost about a six week period
to let people know something was going
to drop and then this these documents
hit
um the documents contained a number of
absolutely shocking revelations actually
part of that was about the ability for
intelligence agencies to hack and
comment their vehicles as Ray was
mentioning earlier another one which I
won't talk much about because I know
it's Ray's favorite topic is the marble
framework in which this it laid out the
cia's um
method of impersonating Russia North
Korean and
royalty who the the third was
um because China Chinese uh win their
perpetrating hats and penetrations of
networks so they would disguise
themselves as being a Chinese
intelligence agency or a Russian
intelligence agency etc etc and this was
their whole framework for how how
precisely to do that at a technical
level
um there was all types of things about
zero day exploits of major commercial
software platforms
um operating systems devices Etc one of
the big Revelations particularly for
activists and independent journalists
and anyone who was using
um encrypted into and encrypted
messaging applications was the cia's
ability to completely bypass encrypted
messaging systems on your mobile device
so that they would penetrate to your
device at the hardware level and
therefore um and operating system and
therefore any encryption that was
occurring in application after that
sorry too late they're already recording
every single keyboard stroke
um so there is no and I just like to be
very clear there is no encrypted
messaging application in or email
service which provides you any type of
personal protection if you are in any
way targeted and if you're not all of
those comms are getting drag knitted
anyway because they will store the
encrypted data packets for the day in
the future that they will then be able
to Via Quantum Computing or otherwise
break the encryption protocols if they
can't already do that which they may
well be able to we just don't know yet
so unfortunately you can have privacy
from like you know some script Kitty
down the road who might try and hack you
but you're not going to get privacy from
the CIA and we've learned that
definitively from Vault seven there had
been some questions prior to that as to
whether or not there was some degree of
security for users
um and that was just completely blown
apart by Vault seven
um but there were other revolutions and
marble framework in particular was very
significant in terms of other things
that were happening in politics and
media and then I will hand you over to
the expert on that array right now oh by
the way I'm I'm I'm still here I'm just
uh moving to a better lighting Source
because I looked a little too Darth
Vader kind of like Dark Night of the
Soul kind of thing so anyway Susie go
ahead what about marble what is marble
well I have to admonish Susie for
spilling the marbles here
[Laughter]
um
as Susie has already indicated uh you
know this gave
um
this gave the CIA with lots of help from
NSA we're talking about a billion
billion billion dollar program here okay
my friends from NSA were there when this
was started so NSA and CIA were in there
together now mobile framework uh allowed
uh people to
fiddle around with uh some of the
evidence and make it seem uh that this
or that intercept or whatever you call
it uh came from North Korea
or Russia or China
or Iran or an Arabic country they worked
in five languages okay now we all
remember all the charges about uh
Russian fingerprints
on some of those
some of those terrible
interventions in the the uh the election
of 2016. that was all hogwash oh yeah
some of it had to do with this uh this
capability to
impute blame to Russia China North Korea
Arabic countries or Iran but others were
just clearly discoverable by people like
Susie who had the expertise uh but yeah
mobile framework was big and I mentioned
before that when this uh when this came
out it only came out because uh as I
understand it and and since you may know
more there had been an attempt in early
March actually it started around
February of 2017 I believe where Julian
was was willing to tell the justice
department
who didn't give
those uh that terribly damaging
information on Hillary and everybody
else uh and in in return for a measure
of Freedom a measure of not being you
know and the negotiations were at a
Tipping Point
when some
some dumb lawyer
who knew the vice head of the Senate
intelligence committee Senator Mark
Warner
he said well hey Senator Warner do you
know about this uh do you know that
there's this trade going on between the
justice department acting and as a agent
of CIA and Wikileaks people you know why
that and want to say no I don't want to
tell me that totally looked into it he
immediately called Comey headed to the
FBI at the time Comey told the justice
department shut that down we're not
going to give Julian uh any any measure
of comfort now
it was just a week later if memory
serves that Julian said okay here it
goes the rest of Vault 7 was released
correct me if I'm wrong uh Susie
I wouldn't
say that it was punitive the rest of the
release because Julian was extremely
committed to maximizing the scale of
Publications and putting as much out
there as possible
um you are correct that there were
indications on being very like politic
here there were indications
um that he was for the first time ever
prepared to not say who did it but who
didn't do it and we know who didn't do
it and we know and in this case it's a
country rather than a person that didn't
do it and we
um
we know that that was absolutely
derailed at the highest levels just as
the engineering of Julian's exposure
expulsion from the Ecuadorian Embassy
was similarly
um orchestrated at the highest levels
um I'm not particularly convinced that
it would necessarily make a difference
one way or the other I don't really what
makes me say that is Trump's failure to
Pardon Snowden or as such
um and yeah he might have got on the
wrong side of Trump by rejecting Trump's
officially not an emissary of trump that
was sent to be an emissary of trump to
the Ecuadorian Embassy
um but
uh we we can't say definitively but
certainly the timeline of events and the
events are as redescribed
um absolutely
no I mean this whole situation of uh
juliusange Edward Snowden you know of
course they fell on them like a ton of
bricks to worn off anybody else but I
has it been effective because
um as far as I know and I'm not as on
top of this as you both are uh has there
been any kind of leak like the Julian
Assange and Edward Snowden leaks well
yeah I mean the
go ahead I mean Susie made the point uh
that a lot of this was to preempt what
uh right happened what uh Ed Snowden did
from anybody else doing it but Ed
Snowden was 2013 right yeah
volt 7
2017 right so I mean there still are
good people around willing to take great
risks to make sure that that we're
informed about some of the mojinos
things going on
now I don't know if it was Schulte or
anybody else but this this attempt to
make sure that this never happened again
fail I witnessed the fact we have
Schulte and hopefully others that will
speak out people of the character of
John kiriako who will speak out on a
matter of principle so you can't shut
good people down forever and uh and the
proof is in the pudding they can try and
they are pretty effective intimidating a
lot of people I give you a little
example here that I people probably
don't know about about two months ago I
said to myself McGovern you know a good
bit about Russia China Ukraine uh you
know the history of all this because
you're so old for God's sake
um look why don't you do a little why
don't you ask somebody to interview you
and let you speak for an hour about how
all has happened okay
and Regis Tremblay a
videographer said okay ray I'll do that
for you and he did on the 6th of July I
called it a taste of the truth
and I took it through my experience
there as a CIA analyst early in the 60s
and so forth and all the way down and I
and I pointed out that look you know I
learned a hell of a lot at government
expense here's my way of of giving back
believe it or not but this is what I
experienced this is what I know okay
called it a taste of the truth
it got up on YouTube
it got all of a sudden 26 000 views
YouTube shut it down
so a taste of the truth was too much for
YouTube well luckily it was saved on bit
shooting a couple other places but this
it doesn't that speak volumes that uh
that the taste of the truth was a little
bit too much tasty for for YouTube so
this is how it is going here uh it's
harder for people to to see what I say
or what I write uh but you know it's
still available and I'm still hopeful
well we do what we can you know there
are reverses but uh we don't stop and uh
you know one of my one of the things
that I'm asked very often McGovern for
God's sake
don't you get tired I mean you've been
doing this for what 20 years now since
you told that you told us all there were
no weapons of mass destruction why what
good is that too don't check your tires
so I tell them this little story a good
friend of mine he was a representative
from Wisconsin his name was Dave Obi
okay he's a good guy who went to church
together okay so he's headed the
Appropriations Committee okay but before
that during Iran Contra he's really
upset that Schultz and Reagan and the
others didn't tell him about Iran Contra
so it brings Schultz toward the end of
this investigation brings him in to to
appear before a subcommittee and he says
now uh
Secretary of State Schultz I would like
to question you about this and Schultz
very uncharacteristically says
Congressman Obi
the American people it's just they're
just sick and tired of this Iran gate
I know he doesn't much of breath he
looks down at Schultz and he says Mr
Schultz
I didn't swear to support and protect
the constitution in the United States
from all enemies foreign and domestic
until I got tired
that's the way it is with us okay we
took that same oath
well even even though the odds are
against this we don't get tired and
maybe maybe we'll come to a no good end
but it isn't because we get tired
well what's happened to me what I find
deeply disturbing about this whole
situation is that this kind of
repression of uh leakers and whatnot
it's spreading like a cancer and uh
because what you said Susie in that
video that I I watched of yours it was
like an hour long video where you went
through a whole host of different issues
and and the notion that these companies
of repression are expanding and
expanding not just into intelligence to
prevent leaks whether you agree with
that or not it's understandable at least
that they would want to prevent leaks
from their own agency but now they are
expanding out to silence people who say
the wrong thing who say the thing that
they don't agree with or who highlight
information that is publicly available
but that they they want to tune down
they don't want people to hear as much
of and this kind of repression is
spreading out and nobody is safe and
it's becoming deeply creepy that uh so
many people now regular civilians quote
unquote feel nervous about touching
certain topics because they're afraid of
the repercussions that they that could
befall them that that you know they
could lose their job or contracts or or
business opportunities or educational
opportunities it it just seems deeply
bizarre and it's not just intelligence
it's also things that are properly the
purview of personal belief or political
opinion that is
frankly inconsequential to the National
Security of a nation and and so that's
what where the part for me uh uh has
really changed because it's sort of like
um the scope of this repression and and
cutting off leaks has expanded and the
remittance has gone Global and and that
I find deeply disturbing because I
myself uh I'm a nobody I'm a stupid
middle-aged YouTuber who's doing these
videos for fun
this is an amusement for me
wait a second there Gonzalo you went to
an Ivy League school uh same yeah
when they accepted me that's why wait a
second don't don't try to disguise the
fact that you have very good pedigree
all right so you're a pretty bright guy
so if you go after you they have good
reason
yeah Ray tone down the the thing I I
promise you 20 bucks after the show for
saying those things
Ray's done his homework I say I'm not
surprised at all
um no but but the thing you see like
what's happened to me I I did a a solo
live stream yesterday about this
particular issue is that in last uh in
the last couple of weeks you know I got
uh suspended from YouTube I I got my
Twitter
um you know uh
eliminated does it permanently suspend
it add 70 000 viewers and it was because
I was uh saying that the Europeans had
essentially committed suicide and you
know that was enough to get me the
platform from Twitter uh and also
um back in April I was uh I was I was
arrested and held by the state Security
Services of the Ukraine and uh they took
my accounts and and what have you um
because I I used to have a fairly large
Channel about 300 000 subscribers and
another one of 150 000 and a Twitter
account of 60 odd thousand people and I
lost access to all that stuff and that
Twitter account for instance which I had
not had access to since the 15th of
April that too was deleted I mean it
just to unperson me it was deeply creepy
no worries no worries
please tell us all about pankoy
hahaha
damn it I wanted to start at censorship
and then to get into the deep
platforming and then before we talk
about pen quote I'll tell you a few
things you don't know about pancake in
fact I might just um tell the whole
world something we don't know about
pancake uh pancake delivery is happening
um regardless of what happens in terms
of crowdfunding though please do donate
at pancake.com
as soon as the broadcast is over I'll
have those links in the description
below chat so
3700 ordinary members of the public who
are sick of getting arbitrary
suspensions and Shadow bands and sending
messages and not knowing if anyone will
even be able to see them and having
moderation actions taken against them
with no transparency about what the
networks are doing and are thirsty for a
not just right or not just left or not
you know partisan platform and actually
want to be able to put their voice out
and be free of the commercial
constraints and not have the data
captured and sold to corporations and
Big Data companies and security agencies
which happens every single day came
together and they raised a hundred and
eighty three thousand dollars uh us and
they funded pancake which is pancake.com
which is a new platform that's going to
free us of all of the constraints that
we have been facing now of course we're
going to be a massive Target of course
we're going to as funny someone was
saying to me um yesterday well what if
YouTube does this to you and what if
Google does this to you and I said to
them I don't think about that when I'm
doing my security planning I think about
targeted access operations at the NSA
and what they're going to do to me I
don't know what YouTube is going to do
to me but the YouTube stuff the lawyers
can worry about but our architecture our
thread assessment model is slightly
different than just like YouTube but
what we're trying to do is give well
what we are in fact doing we've already
built our interface and we're now just
doing our back end Integrations so we
can release our betas to the public is
to give people cryptographic proofs of
the action taken on the network via the
blockchain including our actions as the
network provider which means if we ban
someone if we suspend someone if we
remove some child porn or whatever off
our Network which we absolutely will
remove be all clear about that there is
a cryptographic proof on our blockchain
that we took this action against this
account on this day at this time this is
the reason why this is the moderator ID
that did it so that we are bringing
transparency to we'll just change it
we're fixing the power imbalance between
the platform and the user right it
shouldn't be all about the focus on the
user I actually did the focus on the
platform so the whole network will know
what we as the provider do and can hold
us accountable for that but they also
have cryptographic proof of their
actions that they take when they publish
public content so so if 50 people like
your Quake message on pancake there are
50 blockchain transactions to prove that
those people click that like button on
that piece of content so we can't come
along and unlike it or unretweet you
know and and share it we can't we can't
violate the actions taken by the users
on our Network in the shadows which is
what's happening right now because I am
seeing what I'm seeing absolutely hands
down call me a conspiracy theorists if
you want I'm seeing manufactured
statistics on Twitter they can decide
how many retweets they want to be on
something they can decide how many likes
they want to be on something they can
decide whether or not you see it the
other thing about paintwork is it is
algorithm free your timeline is in
chronological order you see only content
by the people who you followed so it's
completely opt-in for user content if
you didn't follow the account you don't
see this stuff if you unfollow them you
don't see their stuff we don't recommend
stuff we don't um use any
personalization algorithms we don't
decide what we think you might like and
stick it in front of you we have no
advertising no sponsored content nothing
like that you can't buy space on pan on
a pancake timeline there is no mechanism
by which people can pay us for that and
in all we do ask because we don't sell
your data we don't capture your data
it's a peer-to-peer Network you exchange
your data with other people your account
data is on your device all we ask is
that people pay five bucks a month per
user that's it so you pay a five dollar
a month subscription and you are free of
advertising free equipment shop we're
registered outside of U.S jurisdiction
we don't use any U.S infrastructure or
infrastructure of the Empire as a whole
we are domiciled and independent some of
the last independent jurisdictions on
Earth and our Network hosting is there
as well we also don't capture image or
video content and another date we'll
talk about how the technology if you're
interested just go look up pen quick on
YouTube you'll find plenty of stuff now
I've kind of done this in reverse order
because I wanted to talk about the
censorship problem first rather than
talk about pancake
um because what I I'm finding deeply
disturbing is that all of these uh big
platforms the big gum monopolistic
platforms number one they are
deliberately kept as monopolies and they
are protected by the other players the
other Monopoly players uh number two
what I've I've started seeing is that
you're seeing a
government-sponsored trolling going on
on on uh on Twitter it's been a big
thing it started with uh the Ukrainian
situation and it's been expanding and
I'm noticing it that it's happening in
different nuclei of interests where you
have paid trolls that Twitter allows
where anything else they would you know
ban them immediately but these are the
approved trolls the Servants of Empire
yeah exactly they're they're like the
NGO are minions in some countries
starting up a uh a color Revolution you
know what I'm saying and they're in
Twitter and they attack and mass uh
anybody who's saying things that counter
the narrative uh and so it's it's much
more interesting than merely trying to
suppress information it's trying to
discredit it and
um uh make it vanish Into The Ether so
that it just doesn't have a chance to
percolate it's it's like when Mark
Zuckerberg went on Joe Rogan and he
admitted that he
um he he for he made Facebook suppress
the Joe Biden laptop story or the hunter
Biden laptop story uh prior to the
election at the behest of the FBI I mean
this would have been outrageous not 10
years ago uh but now it has been
completely normalized and and that part
of it I there was less shock over that
that is the thing I find shocking and
the government is acting in ways that
are totally fascistic the the
um and I as I said before I am a
political conservative and I'm calling
it fascistic and they are the the
companies are going along with this
because they're they depend on the
government for money they don't want to
make enemies they're playing it safe
um at best they are acting amorally if
you will but the government is certainly
the US government is certainly acting
immorally and you're right the Empire
my my feeling is that especially as the
geopolitical situation begins to
deteriorate further and further for the
United States insofar as having
perceived losses geopolitically that the
repression will intensify I mean if if
people think that the repression is bad
now wait five years it's going to be
much much worse that's my thinking at
this point you Susie see yeah sorry my I
actually haven't been on Twitter for a
while now because I spent all my days
working day and night but on my Twitter
bio
um I say like surveillance censorship is
a for-profit model and that's what I see
so I see that um we talked about the
subcontractors the pyramid scheme of
surveillance Contracting
um and now what I see is the formation
of a pyramid scheme of censorship so it
used to be that these security
contractors would get paid to create
spreadsheets of hundreds of names of
Twitter users and put them forward to
the agencies to check them out and
decide you know how they want to handle
these people what what level of
targeting are these people who want to
do
um now I see exactly the same processes
being used and the same security
contractors being used where the goal is
censorship and suppression of speech
rather than just the pure political the
physical political targeting I just did
want to tell you something just that you
said before you're saying you know just
why me I'm just like some guy I used to
have the same sensation all the time I
was a single man from the suburb with
two kids all I did was go to a activism
movement and try and help feed people
and look after people and get their
messages out like why me and um first of
all there is because they make money
from doing this to you and secondly
because their end goal is to do this to
everyone Mass surveillance is about
collecting all the information all the
data all the communication so even if I
am not an activist or a journalist or
whatever I can still be in that Dragnet
and they bill Benny I'm now going to
trample over all over Bill Benny's
ground age so it's been a couple of
hours with him a few days ago Ray
um he always talks about the two degrees
of separation and how actually for every
one target there are thousands of
targets because they target every single
person you know or have any connection
to an any way in your life and then they
target all of the people that they know
as well so literally I mean I Come From
A New You Know Country in New Zealand
five million people we had 80 known
targets of the gcsb our spy agency
through the time that I was an activist
including kim.com was a major one on
that list
um 18 new zealanders how many people
They Know Each 100 200 each okay well
how many did they know each 100 200 each
250 each
how hard is it to get those two Hawks to
cover the entire friggin country on one
surveillance warrant and they do these
bulk collection warrants now the
collection warrants of the intelligence
agencies aren't on an individual it's
not on Susie from occupy it's on the
city of Auckland that internet service
provider whatever they call them bulk
collection warrants they can nominate a
company a geographic location or get to
this they use this word a class of
people
oh that's a class of people they can get
a bulk collection warrant on so this
really does affect everybody whether
it's because you know someone who knows
someone that is of interest to them they
will rate through your entire life
whether it's because you happen to be in
a location that is of interest to them
or whether you are part of a class of
people what is that is there students at
a university is that people at a church
is that like what is that class of
people we don't really know we know that
the leader um the head of the agency of
the gcsb
um says that he spends a dozen hours you
know going and getting these warrants
but then when they publish the warrant
statistics they only have this tiny
little number that they that they have
um that they admit to having per year so
if you have a tiny number of warrants
but you spend all these hours at
Parliament getting those warrants and
you can place warrants on a geographic
location or class of people what does it
add up to it adds up to we're all
victims the only question is whether you
know it or not um and um I completely
agree we uh I mean we're past the point
of needing another church committee like
we need a freaking Nuremberg for these
people because well we haven't we have
what we haven't got to yet is that
surveillance kills surveillance kills if
you are under surveillance and you know
it it damages your mental health it
damages your relationships they
interfere in every aspect of your life
they literally kill people they drive
them to Suicide some cases they actually
do much worse things that I don't even
want to really talk about but yeah yeah
I mean well the classic example
exactly right when I heard that story I
was like no they crashed his car no no
the the it was it's like the the you
know the two bullets in the back of the
head and it's called suicide you don't
know that that was most definitely
absolutely
yeah they manipulated the um the
automobile by the by the way there were
some interesting data um this uh actress
who who was killed recently and H
there's video evidence of her trying to
stop the car as it was like caruming at
60 miles an hour in some Los Angeles
Suburban Street
and uh it went by some security camera
and you could hear the sound and and if
you're mechanically inclined and know
anything about cars you could hear how
the handbrake had been pulled on the car
because when when you drive a car with
the handbrake uh which is not designed
to do it makes a very distinctive sound
it was clearly that that this poor
woman's car was had been tampered with
and she was corrobing at you know 60 odd
miles an hour 70 miles an hour through
the Suburban Street and eventually
crashed and apparently was killed uh uh
and you know this kind of thing crazy as
it may sound because I'm not one for
conspiracy theories you know I do
believe that Paul is alive and Elvis
dead and Neil Armstrong walked on the
moon but some of the things that come up
you're like no come on come on that
that's that's not how that happened I
mean come on I'm you know I I I I didn't
fall off the tournament truck you know
yesterday it was you know the week
before last but still it's been a while
enough that I'm not that damn stupid you
know but they they consistently push
narratives that are so absurd and they
expect everyone to believe them they
they use their positions of authority to
uh um you know that they're part of the
mainstream media and and whatnot so that
you're sort of like
you you feel impolite to disagree and I
think that that's one of the problems
that we're having Ray
uh Gonzalo a proposed of all this
what happened to John kiriakov I don't
know what happened to him
oh you know he actually he actually
emailed his apologies his internet went
out oh it was choppy and then it was
gone
no he's safe I did yeah he's safe I did
suggest to him that uh he have he's seek
an alternative method of connecting and
hopefully he will come back um I know
he's here with us yeah because uh look
uh the standing offer to John if he's
listening that will I'll be happy to
have him on again at another opportunity
because it was a delight to talk for him
forever briefly
yeah
yes how come I don't hear any uh Rockets
or bombings or anything like that what
have you to add from your pers your
specific uh Vantage Point well um let me
see on September 9th Friday September
9th there was a big strike here in um in
the city of Kharkov they hit a number of
targets they were all about a dozen
targets or a little over a dozen targets
uh within you know minutes of each other
uh it was simultaneous clearly a Russian
I don't know what I mean it was Russian
no question
and um they actually hit one of the
buildings next to mind
I have pretty spectacular pictures but I
can't share them because it shows the
karkov skyline and you could identify or
figure out uh where I'm at and I want to
keep that information private for the
time being uh but um yeah it was it was
um very spectacular but after that and
there were also two blackouts that day
Friday that evening there was a blackout
for about six hours and then on Tuesday
Tuesday last a week ago today there was
another six hour blackout but since then
there hasn't been any blackouts uh there
have been various theories as to why uh
the Russians would have taken out the
electrical Grid in um in in just about
the whole country
um one very shrewd observation that was
made was that this was during the
so-called heart club offensive and uh
Russian forces might have wanted to slow
down the movement of troops because you
see the
um train system works on electricity and
so
um knocking out the power no trains Ergo
you can't move troops and tanks and so
it might have been that or it might have
been a show of force or whatever other
reason and the Russians
um I I mean I I know uh I I know enough
of the Russian military at least that
they don't go to the bathroom without a
plan and they don't do things for no
reason they have very very good reasons
for just about everything that they do
and so if if they did this approach of
knocking out the lights twice but not
bothering after that even though they
could do it whenever they want they must
have had a specific reason for it it
wasn't just you know uh um to um quote
unquote terrorize the population because
in fact these two
um blackouts were the only blackouts
that have been the only blackouts here
in the city of Kharkov since the
beginning of this conflict or more
properly since I arrived here on the 1st
of March because between the 24th of
February and the first of March I was in
Kiev and um and there weren't any
blackouts there either
um uh you know and I came on the first
of March and since then until September
9th the the electricity internet
Everything Mobile phones everything
worked perfectly fine until Friday the
9th for six hours and then uh Tuesday
the 13th for six hours and since then
it's been relatively quiet
um I don't know what is going on
um except what I get from publicly
available sources because you know I'm a
chicken and I just want to stay away
from the bullets and the artillery
shells because they're horrifying and I
don't want any piece of that you know
and and the the people who have had to
suffer a lot of damage and whatnot
because of this conflict you know my
hearts go out to them but uh uh yeah I I
try to stay away from all that and the
information I get really is from the
internet
and I'm saying here
um I originally came here because uh my
uh my wife and my children are here I
had gone to Kiev on business I literally
arrived the night before I was supposed
to be there just for two nights and then
come back but I was stuck there for a
bit and took the train down here
um and uh my wife and children they have
already left they spent the summer in
Western Europe and they had a lovely
time and I stayed here helping out my
in-laws and just you know and and now
quite frankly uh because of my situation
with the sbu they've asked me not to
leave the city and
um and these they told me that if I try
to leave the country they'll know about
it because they'll check me at the
border and that I'll be arrested and so
that's why as a practical matter I
really can't leave
um and uh yeah I'm staying here and
quite frankly I want to see what happens
I want to see how this uh this situation
plays out I'm very very surprised that
it has lasted as long as it has I mean
if you had told me on February 24th that
we'd be into September and this would
still be going on I would have been
truly shocked because I would have
thought that they would have negotiated
a ceasefire and some sort of agreement
and the hostilities
but
um the zonski regime clearly has no
intention of doing that their intent on
fighting to The Bitter End and I think
it's going to be extremely bitter I I
think that um
from the very beginning wasn't has to
understand two things number one this
was an existential War for Russia they
had to prevent Ukraine from joining NATO
and and they and and they certainly were
not going to allow Ukraine to invade the
donbass as they were planning to number
one and that's the first truth and
number two uh the Russian armed forces
are simply better equipped they have
more manpower and they are better LED
and better supplied than the Ukraine
Armed Forces so when you have two
unequal fighters in a ring the result is
inevitable and there's simply no contest
when you have a bantamweight going up
against a heavyweight there's no
question as to what's going to happen
and see if you have and to continue the
metaphor if you have the manager of the
bantamweight
keep it keeps on telling him keep on
going keep on fighting you'll win
against Mike Tyson here in front of you
you are the one who are going to be hurt
and hurt in a way that you won't recover
from and that's the tragedy of the
Ukraine situation they have been goaded
by the West into a war that will destroy
Ukraine destroy a generation of
ukrainians
and because of the Exodus of people
especially the most educated people the
most hard-working people those people
have fled to the west where they were
received with open arms which is all
very nice and good but see they will
have no incentive to return to Ukraine
after the hostilities are over and it's
credibly estimated that something like
11 million people have left Ukraine a
country of 44 million roughly a quarter
of the population has fled the country
some 3 million or a little bit more than
3 million has fled to Russia and the
rest to the west and those people will
never return
how about the uh how about the folks uh
that are still there in haka for example
um is there any War weariness or are
they uh the Patriotic ukrainians or uh
you know how's the man in the street
feel about this Darren
I have a very little uh limited contact
with uh people but I can say that um for
the most part in March the city was
empty I mean I'm talking empty if you
had told me that 80 of the population
had fled the city I would have said yeah
that sounds about right perhaps more
um but now there's a lot of life in the
city a lot of people have come back you
see cars on the roads and going in
different places I mean it seems
semi-normal-ish there are lots of
restaurants that are open and so forth a
lot of businesses though are permanently
closed
um I suspect
okay this is my suspicion but it's it's
fairly it's fairly correct that the
people who came back are Russian ethnic
Russians pro-russia and so that's why
they're here I think that there is the
fundamental expectation that eventually
Russia will take the city
uh because the people who were truly
pro-ukrainian who were Ukrainian ethnic
ukraines they've left them they are not
coming back to karkov this I know for a
fact of certain acquaintances that I
know who are ethnically Ukrainian and
and and and are very anti-russian and
they have no intention of coming back
and so I think that a lot of people who
have come back and who are trying to go
get on with their lives are people who
fully expect themselves to be Russian
citizens within the next year or two uh
and and that is an incredible
possibility because the cities that have
been captured by Russia they've offered
uh the people there to get a Russian
passport and Russian citizenship and
it's a very simple bureaucratic process
the line sometimes can be long but
apparently the process itself takes you
know 15 minutes and you leave there with
a Russian passport
yeah or well actually you leave with a
ticket and then you'll get the Russian
passport but you know what I mean
um but but the thing is see
um
this is a civil war
okay and
um and people are choosing signs and
karkov is a Russian city it is a
traditionally Russian city it is a
majority ethnic Russian uh everybody
speaks Russian here unlike in the west
where they speak Ukrainian and so yeah
the the expectation is that this will
eventually fall to the Russians that's
the expectation at this time good yeah
I'm going to have to leave in about 10
minutes uh yeah we're gonna wind it down
because it's been a great conversation
but you know there's the the song by
Michelle shocked the secret to A Long
Life Is Knowing When it's time to go so
anyway on on that I want to invite you
both to give like a final
um note uh as to the topic that we've
been discussing here
um I should have prepared you before and
told you about it but is there anything
that you want to leave The Listener with
and any final thought that you think
would be worthwhile for them to carry
with them uh after the end of the show
Susie can I throw it to you please
all this so much so much
that is so much having read thousands of
Snowden documents I have a head full of
knowledge that I wish that the average
person had and I can only encourage them
to
um and this goes for Wikileaks documents
too to go to WikiLeaks and actually
search key terms and educate yourself
because a man sacrificed his life and
many other lives have one way or another
been impacted by it for the knowledge
that is sitting in that database just
waiting for people to to consume learn
about how the world really works and in
those documents you'll find them because
when you read the documents of the
agencies you get a completely different
picture than you get watching some you
know CNN produced like short documentary
about them the media does not tell you
the truth about how these agencies work
um it's probably a whole other show for
me to share what I know about the inner
workings of these agencies it's actually
something I would love you to learn
about Gonzalo because I think it
originally impacts your life and when
you uh
when you obtain this type of knowledge
there are
ways in which you can alter your choices
and in your own life which will put you
in a slightly better position than you
would otherwise have been so to be a
Target like you obviously are and I feel
great solidarity with you because your
life is at risk that's a fact and you
are a Target that's a fact
for you I would love you to learn as
much as you can in order to empower
yourself in your own situation
and Julian did exactly that he empowered
targets to better be able to survive
their own situation
in terms of final messages I just want
to say I love Roman government so much
she's one of my favorite people and the
person is on it I call him you want me
to leave so I can leave you two alone
together I don't know
the reason one of the reasons I love
them so much is because it reminds me of
my grandfather who was a World War
cricketer and and who fought from 39
until most nearly all the way through 44
my grandfather and his brother went to
war and only my grandfather came home
and Ray reminds me very much of my
grandfather and so I've always just felt
a natural Affinity to him for that
reason but also because he's a walking
encyclopedia like Julian and when Ray
talks I feel like I can sit here and
listen all night because just as
Wikileaks is a great resource and just
as the snoring documents are a great
resource sitting here and listening to
Rey and his experiences and his
knowledges similarly a resource like
that
um so yeah they really don't have much
else to say except thank you to you for
having me on the show oh my pleasure I
mean somebody whenever you want to
please well um yeah I'd love to talk
about Russia I don't know much about
Ukraine you're actually the only person
I kind of know who's in Ukraine
um Rey is a totally different different
killer fish he will you know an immense
amount about Ukraine I do know about
Russia because I've been here for seven
years and I can give my own experiences
we'll definitely have you on again to
discuss life in Russia yeah that would
be awesome yeah yeah I love you right
yeah and Ray what what final thought
would you like to leave us with
well I'd I'd like to have everyone who's
watching or listening know how to spell
pen quake
it's that tan again that you mentioned
initially and I'm going to spell it and
Susie you correct me if I'm wrong okay
p-a-n-q-u-a-k-e correct okay
now that's that's the outcome of an
immense
effort
uh by people who know what they're doing
and I look I look very hopefully to that
as resource uh for something like The
Fifth Estate that Julian himself created
and enabled us to learn from
the thing I'll simply say is
one of my heroes uh was a Hungarian Jew
named ference
who became an Army lawyer and was one of
the last prosecutors
at noon back
he was asked you know for his advice as
to what we all should do
uh to try to be as tenacious as he was
in pursuing Justice and he said oh he
said is there just three things
you never give up
and you never give up
that's it folks I'm pleased to be with
folks who never give up
and on that note I think that we should
call it a stream I want to thank you all
my gentlemen all my guests rather
including uh John kiriaku uh Susie
Dawson Ray McGovern like I said before
the links to find them will be in the
description below I neglected to do that
before but by the time this this goes up
you'll see it and uh John if you're
listening like I said I'd love to have
you back on again I hope you sort out
your internet issues and Susie and Ray
of course you are always welcome
whenever you'd like to chat thanks so
much I hope you guys uh enjoyed the show
and I will catch you next time take it
easy
right